<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mills Family Resources on M. E. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/</link><description>Recent content in Mills Family Resources on M. E. Mills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mills of Buffalo</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/buffalo-mills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/buffalo-mills/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section introduces the family of William Mills, a first cousin of Edward Mills&amp;rsquo; father Jonas Davis Mills, who lived in western NY during a time that overlaps with the time Edward Mills&amp;rsquo; family was living in Corfu NY, likely less than 20 miles away.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reverend Samuel Wickham Mills’ Genealogical Research</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/mills-samuel-wickham/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/mills-samuel-wickham/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section presents some of the extensive research into the Mills genealogical record done by &lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/58270648/samuel-wickham-mills">Reverend Samuel Wickham Mills&lt;/a> (05 Apr 1820 to 22 Nov 1902) of Orange County NY. Biographical information on Reverend Mills is also presented, along with details of Horatio W. Mills’ death in the Seawanhaka disaster. Both of these Mills are descended from Timothy Mills of Mills Pond, and they are in the same generation as Edward&amp;rsquo;s father Jonas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Battle of Long Island</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/battle-of-long-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/battle-of-long-island/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the Battle of Long Island, the first major battle of the American Revolution after the United States declared independence from England, the British overwhelmingly defeated the Continental Army. Both Jedediah Mills (father of Mary Platt Mills) and William Mills (father of William Mills of Erie County) fought in the battle alongside other Mills family members in Captain Nathaniel Platt’s Smithtown Regiment of Minute Men of Suffolk County, under the command of General Nathaniel Woodhull.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>William Sidney Mount</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/mount-william-sidney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/mount-william-sidney/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/8123/william-sidney-mount">William Sidney Mount&lt;/a> (26 Nov 1807 to 19 Nov 1868) was also descended from &lt;a href="https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/smithtown/">Timothy Mills of Mills Pond&lt;/a>. The Long Island Museum of American Art, History, &amp;amp; Carriages owns many of William Mount&amp;rsquo;s works and the text of this section is taken from the Museum&amp;rsquo;s past exhibitions, reproduced here with permission.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/mills-robert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-family/mills-robert/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following is the research I accumulated on Robert Mills prior to determining that he was likely out-of-scope for this work. As far as I can tell, &lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/77507182/robert-mills">Robert Mills&lt;/a> (17 Nov 1824 to 11 Dec 1890) is not a descendant of Timothy Mills of Mills Pond, although he may be a descendant of John Mills &amp;ldquo;who was made freeman of Boston in 1632&amp;rdquo;. (Genealogies of Long Island Families, p105.)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>