<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Specific Topics on M. E. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Specific Topics on M. E. Mills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>E. H. Mills and M. E. Mills General Stores</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/me-mills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/me-mills/</guid><description>&lt;p>After moving to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners in Mar 1879, Edward restarted his general store on his own, now simply called E. H. Mills. Both Jonas and Emily clerked at E. H. Mills. Emily took over the store after Edward&amp;rsquo;s death and operated it under the name M. E. Mills from 1909 until her death in 1937. Soon thereafter, Jessie Brewer took over the store and ran it under her name for a dozen years, primarily as a notions store with a lending library in the back. In 1961, Charles Vorhis purchased the building and moved the post office there from what is presently known as Brookton&amp;rsquo;s Market. The Mills&amp;rsquo; store structure survives today and is located at 484 Brooktondale Road, better known to current residents as &amp;ldquo;the old postoffice&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills Family in Corfu NY</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/corfu-eh-mills-co/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/corfu-eh-mills-co/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before calling Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners home, the Mills moved to Corfu NY in the early 1860&amp;rsquo;s where Edward, along with partners Charles Pine and James Hillyer, started E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. &amp;ldquo;cash store&amp;rdquo; offering general merchandise and dry goods. Horace clerked in his father’s store, and Mary Ann was a member of First Presbyterian Church of Corfu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills Family in Staten Island NY</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/staten-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/staten-island/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward and Mary Ann began their marriage in Staten Island NY where they lived throughout the 1850&amp;rsquo;s and where each Mills child was born. Here, Edward likely learned the grocery business from Mary Ann&amp;rsquo;s brother, &lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/199952123/charles-m-pine">Charles Mills Pine&lt;/a> (1812 to 08 Oct 1897), who eventually co-owned E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. in Corfu. Pine&amp;rsquo;s general store was located in West New Brighton, also known as Factoryville, a neighborhood in the Staten Island town of Castleton, and was at different times known as C. M. Pine &amp;amp; Co., Pine Hillyer &amp;amp; Co., and C. M. Pine &amp;amp; Son. The Mills are members of the Reformed Dutch Church of Port Richmond, where Charles Pine was a longtime member of the church consistory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hempstead NY and Pine Genealogy</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/hempstead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/hempstead/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward presumably moved to Hempstead with his family in 1837. There, he met his first wife, Mary Ann Pine, and her brother and Edward&amp;rsquo;s mentor in business, Charles Mills Pine. The Mills and the Pines attended Christ&amp;rsquo;s First Presbyterian Church.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mills Pond NY and Mills Genealogy</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/genealogy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/genealogy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward H. Mills&amp;rsquo; ancestors were early settlers of Edward&amp;rsquo;s birthplace, the Town of Smithtown on Long Island, and to this day the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mills_Pond_District_(St._James,_New_York)">Mills Pond District&lt;/a> is named for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temperance Activity</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/temperance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/temperance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The temperance movement was a significant cultural phenomenon of the mid 1800&amp;rsquo;s to the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s, and was particularly strong among the religious communities of upstate NY. There was significant overlap between members of the temperance movement and those supporting suffrage, and before that, abolition. Emily, Hannah and Ellen were all active in temperance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emily’s Brookton Baptism</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/baptism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/baptism/</guid><description>&lt;p>07 Apr 1907, fifteen people that included Emily Mills and Jessie Brewer are baptized at Brookton Congregational Church, in a service officiated by Reverend Annis Ford Eastman on one of her last visits to Brookton.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relevant Census Data</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/census/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/census/</guid><description>&lt;p>A summary of all of the census data of Edward Mills&amp;rsquo; family that I have been able to access.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>George Richardson</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/richardson-george/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/richardson-george/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/189275611/george-h-richardson">George H. Richardson&lt;/a> (May 1862 to 26 Feb 1938) was employed at E. H. Mills in Brookton during the time that Edward Mills was Brookton Postmaster. George subsequently opened his own grocery business in Personius Hall at present day 559 Brooktondale Road and also supplied groceries to farmers from his delivery wagon two days a week. George moved his family to Ithaca in 1905.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hallocks in Caroline</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/caroline-hallocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/topics/caroline-hallocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although there is likely no direct connection between the two families, it is interesting to note that there are a number of Hallocks in the Danby and Caroline area coinciding with the Mills&amp;rsquo; time in the area. But obviously, if these Hallocks are related to Edward&amp;rsquo;s mother, it would certainly suggest reasons why Edward chose to move the family to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>