<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mills' Home, Brooktondale on M. E. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/</link><description>Recent content in Mills' Home, Brooktondale on M. E. Mills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deeds and Other Past Owners</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/other-past-owners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/other-past-owners/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section explores the historical deeds and the lives of some of the other former owners of the home beginning in the 1860&amp;rsquo;s with the first presumed owner, William Benton Wolcott, through to the 1960&amp;rsquo;s ownership by Jessie (Shurter) Brewer. It is unclear exactly when the Mills family first moved into the home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mill Race Bridge and The Barn</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/mill-race-bridge-barn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/mill-race-bridge-barn/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the 1860&amp;rsquo;s, when Brooktondale was called Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners, and Brooktondale Road was called Creek Road, the Personius Flouring Mills stood where Dalebrook apartments sit presently, almost directly across the street from Mills&amp;rsquo; Store, better known to many today as &amp;ldquo;The Old Postoffice&amp;rdquo;. The Mills&amp;rsquo; Home parcel was sub-divided from the grist mill property, and it was originally referred to as &amp;ldquo;the Wolcott lot&amp;rdquo; for William Benton Wolcott, the first owner of record. The mill race bridge is one of the primary landmarks used to establish the place of beginning for the Mills&amp;rsquo; Home parcel from the time of its original sub-division from the grist mill to the end of Emily Mills&amp;rsquo; life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Jones, Lattin, and Talmadge Years</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/jones-lattin-talmadge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/jones-lattin-talmadge/</guid><description>&lt;p>A compilation of information and photographs from the late 1960&amp;rsquo;s to the mid 2000&amp;rsquo;s, during the years the home was owned by C. Dalton and Clara B. Jones, then Larry and Janet Lattin, and then by Andrea Talmadge. Each set of owners did much to improve the home and property that is still evident presently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Other Features of the Property</title><link>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/property-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/family-of-edward-hallock-mills/mills-home/property-features/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section explores various features of the Mills’ Home property, including the stone foundation and the “large oak tree”.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>